<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Actions>
  <Action id="sendMessage" deviceFilter="self.messagesAppDevice">
    <Name>Send Message using the Messages App</Name>
    <CallbackMethod>sendMessage</CallbackMethod>
    <ConfigUI>
      <Field id="message" type="textfield" default="">
	<Label>Message to Send:</Label>
      </Field>
      <Field id = "sep" type = "separator"/>
      <Field id = "explanation" type="label">
	<Label>In the "Message to Send" field above, you can insert device substitution markup which will substitute a variable value just before the action is run. Simply insert %%v:VARIABLEID%% anywhere in the text as many times as you want. VARIABLEID is the variable's numeric id as found in the Variable List window. Likewise, you can substitute device state values by inserting %%d:DEVICEID:STATEKEY%% where DEVICEID is the device's numeric identifier and STATEKEY is the state identifier as found in the documentation for built-in devices and in the Custom States tile in the control area of the Home screen for custom plugin devices (which you may have to scroll the bottom panel of the Home screen to see).</Label>
      </Field>
    </ConfigUI>
  </Action>
  <Action id="markAsRead" deviceFilter="self.messagesAppDevice">
    <Name>Mark current message as Read, and allow the next one to be fetched</Name>
    <CallbackMethod>markAsRead</CallbackMethod>
  </Action>
  <Action id="receiveMessage">
    <Name>Receive a message from the Messages App</Name>
    <CallbackMethod>receiveMessage</CallbackMethod>
    <ConfigUI>
      <Field id="info" type="label">
	<Label>In order to receive messages from Messages.app, go to the Messages.app Preferences, choose the General tab, and change the value of "AppleScript handler" to "Open Scripts Folder". Copy the Run Indigo Message Plugin Action.applescript file into that directory, then close and re-open Messages.app Preferences, and select the Run Indigo Message Plugin Action in the AppleScript handler list. Due to a bug in Messages, new messages will not always reach Indigo if Messages.app is in the foreground, so put an Indigo window in front of it and it should start working.</Label>
      </Field>
    </ConfigUI>
  </Action>
</Actions>
